<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<page>
    <order>4</order>
    <title>Feats and Fighting Styles</title>
    <section>
        <header>Feats</header>
        <subsection>
            <header>Dual Wielder (Requires: 13 Strength or 13 Dexterity)</header>
            <text>You can draw or stow two one-handed weapons when you would normally be able to draw or stow only one. When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can make your additional attack with your offhand weapon as part of a Standard Action Attack or a Reaction Action Attack, but no longer with a bonus action attack. </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Elvish Accuracy</header>
            <text>Does not grant +1 to a stat</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Grappler / Tavern Brawler</header>
            <text>These feats are merged </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Heavy Armor Master</header>
            <text>Reduces all physical damage by half your proficiency bonus (rounded up) when wearing heavy armor </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Martial Adapt (Requires: Requires either 13 Strength or Dexterity)</header>
            <text> </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Martial Initiate (Requires: Proficiency in at least one martial weapon)</header>
            <text>+1 to Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution.  Learn a Fighting Style</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Polearm Master (Requires: 13 Dexterity)</header>
            <text> </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Sentinel (Requires: 13 Strength)</header>
            <text> </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Sharpshooter (Requires: Requires 13 Dexterity)</header>
            <text>Instead of -5 attack +10 damage, it is -(Proficiency) attack and +(Proficiency) damage </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Great Weapon Master (Requires: Requires 13 Strength)</header>
            <text>Instead of -5 attack +10 damage, it is -(Proficiency) attack and +(Proficiency) damage </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Heavy Toss (Requires: Requires 13 Strength)</header>
            <text>Attacking at long range with a thrown weapon doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls. Your thrown weapons ignore half cover and three-quarters cover. If you throw a weapon at standard range, add half your proficiency bonus (rounded up) to damage</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Deep Rites (Requires: Triton Race)</header>
            <text>You learn more of the magic typical of triton. You learn the 'Speak with Animals' spell and can cast it at will, without expending a spell slot. You also learn 'Pass without Trace' and 'Speak with Plants', each of which you can cast once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast those two spells in this way when you finish a long rest. Wisdom or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for all three spells, depending on the stat bonus you chose.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Beastfolk Evolution (Requires: Beastfolk Race)</header>
            <text>You gain +1 to an attribute and one of the following:</text>
        </subsection>
        <list>
            <header>Glide: </header>
            <text> You have ray-like fins that you can use as wings to slow your fall or allow you to glide. When you fall and aren't incapacitated, you can subtract up to 100 feet from the fall when calculating falling damage, and you can move up to 2 feet horizontally for every 1 foot you descend. </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Monkey's Grip:</header>
            <text> When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal. As a bonus action, you can make an additional natural weapon attack. </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Nimble: </header>
            <text> You can take the Dash or Disengage action as a bonus action on each of your turns. </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Venomous:</header>
            <text> You gain the Acid Splash cantrip and poison resistance </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Amphibious:</header>
            <text>  You can breathe underwater and have cold resistance.</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Predator:</header>
            <text>  Immediately after you use the Dash action on your turn and move at least 20 feet, you can make one melee attack with your natural weapon as a bonus action.</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Fighting Styles</header>
        <subsection>
            <header>Marksmanship</header>
            <text>You ignore the loading quality of crossbows and firearms with which you are proficient. Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls. You gain a +1 to Attack Rolls with crossbows and firearms </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Great Weapon Fighting</header>
            <text>When you make an attack with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you also deal your strength bonus in damage to another target that is adjecent to both you and your main target, as long as the attack roll value would also hit the additional targets AC.  This damage is not an attack and cannot be increased by crit damage or riders.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Weapon Throw Fighting</header>
            <text>You have a +1 to Attack and Damage with weapons that have the Thrown tag, and can treat them as if they had the ammunition tag </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Two Weapon Fighting</header>
            <text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, your weapons do not need to be light, and you add your ability modifier to the offhand damage. </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Tactician</header>
            <text>You learn a maneuver of your choice from the battlemaster archetype, and one superiority dice, which is a d4, unless you have dice that are higher.</text>
        </subsection>
    </section>
</page>