<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<page>
    <order>6</order>
    <title>Pantheon</title>
    <section>
        <header>Pantheon and Culture</header>
        <text>Different cultures can have different beliefs about the divine.  Below is a table showing as such, with the Head Diety marked with an asterisk *</text>
        <table>
            <header> </header>
            <column>Domain</column>
            <column>Akrosi Empire</column>
            <column>Twin Cities</column>
            <column>Joanapur</column>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Arcana</cell>
                <cell>Old Crow Yore</cell>
                <cell>Old Crow Yore</cell>
                <cell>Old Crow Yore</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Forge</cell>
                <cell>Cadmeum*</cell>
                <cell>-</cell>
                <cell>-</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Grave</cell>
                <cell>Astraeus</cell>
                <cell>Astraeus</cell>
                <cell>Astraeus</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Knowledge</cell>
                <cell>Zurai</cell>
                <cell>Zurai</cell>
                <cell>Zurai</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Life</cell>
                <cell>Tetele</cell>
                <cell>Tetele</cell>
                <cell>Saido</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Light</cell>
                <cell>Aegiter</cell>
                <cell>Muru*</cell>
                <cell>Aegiter</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Nature</cell>
                <cell>Gaia</cell>
                <cell>Gaia</cell>
                <cell>Gaia</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Order</cell>
                <cell>Lady and Fate</cell>
                <cell>Bast and Nekhen</cell>
                <cell>Lady and Fate*</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Tempest</cell>
                <cell>Arkun</cell>
                <cell>Mitzriti</cell>
                <cell>Mitzriti</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>Trickery</cell>
                <cell>Lurere</cell>
                <cell>Lurere</cell>
                <cell>Lurere</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <header>John</header>
                <cell>War</cell>
                <cell>Kromgol</cell>
                <cell>Kromgol</cell>
                <cell>Kromgol</cell>
            </row>
        </table>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Old Crow Yore</header>
        <text>The purple garbed clergy of Old Crow Yore are few and far between, but are amongst the most powerful spellcasters the world knows. While Zurai might have some knowledge of this gods secrets, as a diety, Yore also has the wisdom to use it. Every spell is written into his books. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Bundle of Raven Feathers</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Sometimes appearing as a crow or raven, other time as a humanoid with a crow's head</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Cadmeum</header>
        <text>The newest god who in his life was a hero of the dwarves. He died of mysterious circumstances, but took the tests in the Halls of Ascension and was deemed worthy of apotheosis by Astraeus. As a god, Cadmeun is the patron diety of dwarves, but will aid any who hold crafting or civilization sacred. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Valknaut on a hammer</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>A dwarf in brass armor with a forge hammer and shield</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Astraeus</header>
        <text>One of the oldest gods and formerly a titan, Astraeus judges those who pass onto the afterlife. Her clerics perform funeral rites and guard sacred or ruined places. Despises undead. At the end of time, she guards the Halls of Ascension and acts as a gatekeeper to those who have ambitions of Apotheosis </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Scales of Justice</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>A blind, stern female giant in roman garb</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Zurai</header>
        <text>The god of secrets, pacts, and forbidden knowledge. Followers of Zurai tend to keep their secrets to themselves, but will gladly trade for secrets others hold. It is said that those born with heterochromia are those touched by the all seeing Diety.</text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>An Eclipse of the sun that resembles an eye</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Androgynous, ambiguous figure robed and hooded, or a cluster of eyes in the dark</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Tetele</header>
        <text>Tetele seeks balance in all things, for without the blackest night, there is no light in the dark. Her clergy provide healing and restoration to any who need it, even opposite sides of a conflict. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>A trident with two dots, one black; one white</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>A robed humanoid with a trident</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Saido</header>
        <text>A god of redemption and freedom, who opens safe passages to the troubled </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>A white speartip raised in the dark</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Cloaked figure with a spear that shifts into many forms</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Muru</header>
        <text>A god who was reborn after being fractured. His restoration came with fire being gifted to mortals, and his worship is the most common throughout the realms, from those who tend the flame, to those who let it spread wildly. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Sun with concentric lines through it </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Giant with many lined tattoos </text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Aegitar</header>
        <text>A god who around the time of Joan of Spines, had an enormous cult following that their leader had ascended to divinity.  Their chief believe is humanity is both protected and cleansed by fire. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Lightning bolt and fire </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Bearded man with glowing eyes</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Arkun</header>
        <text>A god of the Tempest, who was pierced by a god slaying lance yet survived, who now rests in the fields of Elysium, guarding its fruit from would be trespassers. Followers of Arkun pray that they can survive through harrowing journeys </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Twin Hurricanes forming infinity</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>An orc, resting against a tree, much of his body is replaced with steel machinations </text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Gaia</header>
        <text>The goddess of the soil and sea, and all that spring forth from it, her domain is the whole world. It is said that she will wake when the world ends, and all of creation is her dream. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text> Flower infinitely blooming</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>A sleeping elf woman in the boughs of a tree</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Lovers Lady Luck and Lord Fate</header>
        <text>The twin gods Lady and Lord are locked in an eternal game of chess to prove who is superior. As the gods of luck and destiny, they use the entire world as their game board, and all people as playing pieces. Most everyone is a worshiper of the binary gods, even if its entirely by accident. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>A Icosahedron with varying symbols on each side</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Appears as a well groomed, well dressed human couple, usually garbed in the cultural clothes that best apply to the situation, or at random</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Brothers Bast and Nekhan</header>
        <text>The two brother gods Bast and Nekhan are two different types of Order.  Born of Muru,  Bast believes in the outcome over the means, and Nekhan believes in the beauty of ideals over the outcome.  </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>An angular version of yin and yang </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Bast appears as a bald man with a beard, Nekhan is clean shaven with long hair </text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
    <header>Metzriti</header>
        <text>A nature god whos wrath caused her to become a tempest. Believes the world should be returned to its natural state, and abhors technology, seeing it as a corruption of nature. Her followers disavow Cadmeun, and join the wild hunt in their purpose. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>Tree Roots that appear as lightning</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>A small humanoid with green hair</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Lurere</header>
        <text>Lurare is associated with the hunt, venoms, and herbalism, and her worshipers include both would be assassins and hunters of beast. Certain rites can summon her to bless a hunt, but only once. Summoning a second time will lead to certain death. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>An arrowhead in the mouth of a skull</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Bat looking beastfolk</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Kromgol</header>
        <text>As a mortal, Kromgol died defending his tribe from titans, dragons, and megafauna. The power of belief pushed him into godhood, and while he has a bias towards his people, he accepts any who devote themselves body and soul to combat and warfare. Kromgol's clergy believe that only through struggles can we better ourselves. </text>
        <list>
            <header>Symbol: </header>
            <text>A spiral with jagged edges</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Appearance:</header>
            <text>Appear as a proud orc wearing the skins of many beasts</text>
        </list>
    </section>
</page>