<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<page>
    <order>2</order>
    <title>Races</title>
    <section>
        <header>Human</header>
        <text>Humans make up a majority of the humanoids in Wayward, and about tie with Dwarves for being the most populated race in Akros. Humans are quick to spread out and settle new areas, and are quick to adapt their environment to suit them. </text>
        <subsection>
            <header>Options</header>
            <text>When making a human in wayward, you can choose Human, Variant Human, Lightfoot Halfling, or Stout Halfling racial stats. Can take any human or halfling feats.</text>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Dwarves</header>
        <text>Although more traditional dwarves live to the north, the tribes that settled a bit farther south created the Akrosi Empire. Their culture has a tendency towards order and craftsmenship, which they apply to the task of empire building. The Dwarvern Origin story tells of stones that walked from the veins of the earth, and as they traveled upwards, they became more and more made of flesh instead of rock. </text>
        <subsection>
            <header>Options</header>
            <text>When making a dwarf in wayward, you can choose Mountain Dwarf, Hill Dwarf, Rock Gnome or Forest Gnome. Can take any Dwarf or Gnome feats.</text>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Elves</header>
        <text>While most races change the environment to suit them, the Elves do the opposite. While many elves have been adapted to city or natural environments, some are more feylike and change with the seasons. Elves are said to come from another place, a home that fell that they can no longer return to. Because of their long lives, and low birth rates, many elf lines situate themselves in positions of power in society.</text>
        <subsection>
            <header>Options</header>
            <text>When making an Elf in wayward, you can choose High Elf, Wood Elf, Eladrin (MTF), or Half Elf. Can take Elvish feats.</text>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Orc</header>
        <text>Orc culture doesn't subscribe in the practice of staying in one place. They are shamans, hunters, gatherers and caravan traders. They have a deep tradition of storytelling and living in nature, worshiping the gods Kromgol and Arkun.</text>
        <subsection>
            <header>Options</header>
            <text>When making an Orc in wayward, you can choose Half Orc, Orc, or Firbolg stats. Can take any Orc or Human feats.</text>
        </subsection>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Beastfolk</header>
        <text>The race with the most genetic diversity, most resembles a large catlike humanoid, though other animal features sometimes present themselves. Legends say that beastfolk were born of a curse. However, curses can be blessings and blessings can turn to be curses. Such is an idea that influences beastfolk culture. </text>
        <subsection>
            <header>Stat Bonus</header>
            <text>Wisdom +2, Choose Strength or Dexterity +1 Speed 30ft., Choose 20 ft. Swim or 20 ft. Climb </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Age</header>
            <text>Young beastfolk grow quickly. They walk hours after being born, attain the size and development of a 10-year-old human child by the age of 3, and reach adulthood by 15. They live to be around 80.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Natural Senses</header>
            <text>Pick Proficiency in two: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, Survival, or Darkvision.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Natural Armor</header>
            <text>You have tough skin or Fur. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor. </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Natural Weapon</header>
            <text>You have a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier. At character generation, you choose whether this damage is Bludgeoning, Piercing, or Slashing damage.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Languages</header>
            <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language of your choice.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Beastfolk Evolution (Feat)</header>
            <text>You gain +1 to an attribute and one of the following:</text>
        </subsection>
        <list>
            <header>Glide: </header>
            <text> You have ray-like fins that you can use as wings to slow your fall or allow you to glide. When you fall and aren't incapacitated, you can subtract up to 100 feet from the fall when calculating falling damage, and you can move up to 2 feet horizontally for every 1 foot you descend. </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Monkey's Grip:</header>
            <text> When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal. As a bonus action, you can make an additional natural weapon attack. </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Nimble: </header>
            <text> You can take the Dash or Disengage action as a bonus action on each of your turns. </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Venomous:</header>
            <text> You gain the Acid Splash cantrip and poison resistance </text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Amphibious:</header>
            <text>  You can breathe underwater and have cold resistance.</text>
        </list>
        <list>
            <header>Predator:</header>
            <text>  Immediately after you use the Dash action on your turn and move at least 20 feet, you can make one melee attack with your natural weapon as a bonus action.</text>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <header>Triton</header>
        <text>A deep sea race that has a symbiotic relationship with plantlife. In the last 100 years, the Triton have migrated from the ocean depths to land, to escape disease and monsters.  They still long for the place they call "The land of dreams and shadows".  When making a Triton, you gain the following racial traits from below </text>
        <subsection>
            <header>Stat Bonus</header>
            <text>Strength +1, Constitution +1, Choose Wisdom or Charisma +1 </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Age</header>
            <text>Tritons reach maturity around age 15 and can live up to 200 years. </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Amphibious</header>
            <text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet, and can breath both air and water.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Triton Martial Training</header>
            <text>You have proficiency with the spear, trident, light crossbow, and net.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Nereid Knowledge</header>
            <text>You have proficiency in the Nature skill.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Photosynthesis</header>
            <text>As long as you have access to a body of water and sunlight for 8 hours a day, Tritons only need to eat once a week.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>One with Nature</header>
            <text>You know one cantrip of your choice from the druid spell list. Wisdom or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it, depending on the stat bonus you chose.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection>
            <header>Deep Rites (Feat)</header>
            <text>You learn more of the magic typical of triton. You learn the 'Speak with Animals' spell and can cast it at will, without expending a spell slot. You also learn 'Pass without Trace' and 'Speak with Plants', each of which you can cast once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast those two spells in this way when you finish a long rest. Wisdom or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for all three spells, depending on the stat bonus you chose.</text>
        </subsection>
    </section>
</page>